Guide to the It's Only Rock 'N' Roll Collection
The Wittliff Collections
It's Only Rock 'N' Roll Collection
1978-1982
The Wittliff Collections https://www.thewittliffcollections.txstate.edu
Young, Ron (1950-2017)
SWWC.135
2 Linear Feet
1 boxes
Ron Young, longtime music journalist, songwriter and, musician grew up in San Antonio, Texas, and was the founder and publisher of the pioneering indie music newspaper It's Only Rock 'N' Roll. The publication chronicled the rise of punk and New Wave music in San Antonio and Austin, as well as local and regional rock 'n' roll, blues and heavy metal acts.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Nikki Young, 2018. Chris Smart donated 3 issues (Aug 2981, Sept 1981, and March, 1982) in 2019.
Biographical Note
Ron Young was the founder and publisher of the pioneering indie music newspaper It's Only Rock 'N' Roll. The longtime music journalist, songwriter and musician grew up in San Antonio, where he graduated from Robert E. Lee High School. He studied journalism at the University of Texas at Austin. Young was an avid record collector and in the 1970s was a columnist and music critic at the daily newspaper San Antonio Light, and later a regular contributor to the San Antonio Express-News. The easygoing writer once described himself as the Bob Newhart of rock and roll. Young later moved to Nashville, Tennessee and became a published songwriter. He died in San Antonio from complications of cancer on May 11, 2017. He was 67.
Scope and Contents
It's Only Rock 'N' Roll was an indie music newspaper published in San Antonio from May 1978 to April 1982. The publication chronicled the rise of punk and New Wave music in San Antonio and Austin, reporting on national touring acts like Blondie, Elvis Costello, Patti Smith, the Ramones, the Clash and the Sex Pistols, as well as local and regional rock 'n' roll, blues and heavy metal acts. Issues included record reviews, guest columns, nightclub listings and numerous photographs. Included here are 44 issues, from March 18, 1978 through April 1982. Note: The November 1980 issue was mislabeled as Volume 4, number 8.
Index Terms
Subjects
Newspapers; Music -- Texas -- Periodicals
Document Types
Journalism -- Texas
- Volume 1, March 1978 - April 1979
  - Judas Priest cover, March 18, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Beach Boys cover, May 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Elvis Costello cover, June 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Full House cover (Ray Charles, Nick Lowe, Bruce Springsteen, Ann Wilson, Patti Smith, July 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - AC-DC cover; Patti Smith interview, August 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - UFO cover, September 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Cheap Trick, Talking Heads cover, November 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Sammy Hagar cover, December 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Van Halen cover, February 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Steve Martin cover, March 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Judas Priest, The Police cover, April 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Volume 2, May 1979 - April 1980
  - Doug Sahm, Heyoka, Toto cover, May 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Joe Jackson cover, June 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Badfinger, Triumph, AC-DC cover, July 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Sirius, Nazareth, Robert Fripp cover, August 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Battle of the Bands cover, September 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Joe King Carrasco cover, October 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Riot cover, November 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Scorpions cover, December 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - ZZ Top cover, February 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Rush cover, March 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - John Cale, Christopher Cross cover, April 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Volume 3, May 1980 - April 1981
  - Van Wilks, The Beat, Mahogany Rush cover, May 1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 999, Grace Slick, Triumph, Alice Cooper cover, June 1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Judas Priest cover, July 1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Blue Oyster Cult cover, August 1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Fleetwood Mac cover, September 1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Graham Parker cover, October 1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ian Anderson cover, November 1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bruce Springsteen cover, December 1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Van Morrison cover, February 1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Joe King Carrasco cover, March 1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Chuck Berry cover, April 1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Volume 4, May 1981 - March 1982
  - Brave New Music Festival cover, May 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bob Marley cover, June 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Iron Maiden cover, July 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Roky Erickson cover, August 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Ramones cover, September 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Riot cover, October 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Echo and the Bunnymen, Psychedelic Furs cover, November 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - King Crimson cover, December 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Critics Poll cover, February 1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - U2 cover, April 1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Krayolas cover, March 1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)